bhpbilliton.com 2019-04-23

# BHP | Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

Protecting your privacy is very important to BHP. We are committed to maintaining the security of all Personal Information provided to BHP, whether by individuals with whom we do business, visitors to and users of our websites or otherwise. This Privacy Policy details how we collect, use and manage this Personal Information.

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy and applicable data protection and privacy laws:

  * “ **Personal Information** ” is defined as information and data, whether recorded in a material form or not, relating to an identified or identifiable natural person that is processed by or on behalf of BHP, whether or not by automated means; and
  * BHP is considered the “data controller” in respect of the Personal Information that it collects, uses and manages in connection with this Privacy Policy.

**Whose information do we collect?**

BHP collects Personal Information from a range of individuals in the context of its business activities, including:

  * representatives of our suppliers, customers, sponsors and business partners;
  * contractors;
  * landowners;
  * industry association representatives;
  * users of the BHP website; and
  * job applicants.

**What information we collect and why we collect it**

We collect Personal Information from you where it is relevant for our purposes as further detailed below.

Business use

BHP may collect a range of information in a business context, such as your name, gender, job title, photographic identification, email address, home address and other contact details, details of your business and other interests, experience and/or academic and professional qualifications, third party references, communications with you (including notes from meetings and telephone call recordings), feedback or survey responses that you provide to us, financial and payment information, and information collected from clearance questionnaires and/or interviews.

BHP uses information collected from you for business-related purposes, including negotiating, concluding and performing contracts, managing business relationships, administering real estate leases and licences, recruitment, conducting clearance procedures, managing accounts and records, communicating with you and third party contacts, supporting corporate social responsibility activities, security, legal, regulatory and internal investigations and debt administration.

Our website

When you use our website, BHP collects certain standard information that is sent by your browser to our website. This includes technical information, such as your IP address, browser type, operating system, language, time zone setting, access times and any referring website addresses.

BHP uses this information to administer our website and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes. BHP also collects certain information to provide users with a personalised experience when visiting our websites. Through the use of a ‘cookie’, BHP can record information about your visit to our website including the clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time), the pages visited, page interaction information and methods used to browse away from the page. This information is used anonymously and in aggregate, and is collected and logged for statistical purposes. Through analysis of these records, BHP is able to provide an improved service when users revisit our websites. See below for further information on our use of cookies and related technologies.

Other than as stated in this Privacy Policy, no attempt is made to identify our website users or their browsing activities except:

  * where a law enforcement agency exercises a warrant to inspect logs or any such information is otherwise required to be produced by BHP to authorities or regulators; or
  * where BHP believes it is required to collect and produce relevant electronic documentation to fulfil its obligations to third parties, including statutory organisations under local law.

Access to other websites via hyperlink

**Other websites that may be accessible via hyperlinks from the BHP website are owned and operated by third parties and are not subject to the BHP Privacy Policy. BHP has no control over the content of those websites. Please review the privacy policy of each individual website you access and assess whether the policy is satisfactory to you before you use the other websites.**

Cookies & Related Technologies

Our websites and mobile applications (“apps”) use cookies. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website or use an app. Cookies collect information about users and their visit to the website or use of the app, such as their Internet protocol (IP) address, how they arrived at the website (for example, through a search engine or a link from another website) and how they navigate within the website or app. A cookie cannot read data from your hard disk or read cookie files created by other websites.

BHP uses cookies and other technologies to facilitate your internet sessions and use of our apps, offer you services according to your preferred settings, track use of our websites and apps and to compile statistics about activities carried out on our web sites and/or through our apps.

You may set up your web browser to block cookies or remove cookies stored from your computer or mobile device. However, if you do so, you may not be able to use certain features and functions of our websites and apps.

Providing Personal Information

At times, BHP may ask you to voluntarily supply Personal Information, such as your name, email address, location, telephone number and preferred means of communication, for purposes such as subscribing to BHP news alerts or requesting further information from BHP, including through the Contact us form available on our website.

Where we ask you to voluntarily supply Personal Information we will use it to provide you with the information or services that you have requested from us.

Job vacancy website 

When you subscribe to BHP's online job vacancy website, we will collect more specific Personal Information about you, such as your name, email address and telephone number, qualifications and career history. We may also ask you for other information, such as information on your interests and the types of jobs you are interested in. The Personal Information you provide to BHP via this job vacancy website will only be processed for the purpose of considering employment or internship positions at BHP.

In the event that any job application you make is unsuccessful, BHP may choose to retain your Personal Information for a period of up to 12 months for the purposes of considering you for other roles within BHP. BHP is under no obligation to retain your Personal Information for this purpose and may elect to delete your Personal Information at any time following an unsuccessful application. You may also request that BHP deletes your Personal Information in the event that you do not wish to be considered for further roles. You can do this by unchecking the relevant box when you first sign-up to the job vacancy website, or at any time after submitting an application, by emailing us at jobs@bhpbilliton.com.

Please note that in the event that we delete any of your Personal Information relating to a job application that you have submitted (whether at our option or at your request), we will not deactivate your account on our job vacancy website, unless you specifically request that we do so. Therefore you will still be able to log-in and apply for other roles.

If at any time your account remains inactive for a period of at least 12 months, we will contact you to ask if you wish for your account to remain live. If we do not hear from you after a further period of at least 6 months, or if you ask us to do so, we will deactivate your account. Following deactivation, all of your account information will be destroyed or erased from our systems in accordance with our standard information retention and destruction policies.

Sensitive Personal Information

Sensitive Personal Information revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade-union membership, health or medical conditions, genetic or biometric information, sexual orientation, or criminal convictions and offences may be processed by BHP if such processing is necessary to comply with laws and regulations or where you provide this information voluntarily or otherwise consent for us to do so.

Email monitoring

BHP may monitor emails sent to and from its workforce, which may contain Personal Information relating to third parties. The information contained in such emails may be used for business-related purposes, for example when investigating incidents within BHP. Although BHP endeavours not to review the contents of personal emails, there may be occasions on which this is necessary, for example, to investigate a breach of security within BHP, or in the context of legal proceedings.

**The legal basis for BHP processing your Personal Information**

In order to comply with applicable data protection and privacy laws, BHP is required to set out the legal basis for the processing of your Personal Information. In accordance with the purposes for which we collect and use your Personal Information, as set out above, the legal basis for BHP processing your Personal Information will typically be one of the following:

  * your consent;
  * the performance of a contract that we have in place with you or other individuals;
  * BHP or our third parties’ legitimate business interests; or
  * compliance with our legal obligations.

**Disclosure of the information we collect**

BHP may share your Personal Information with people within the company who need to know that information for business or legal reasons, for example, in order to carry out an administrative function such as processing an invoice, or to direct a query that you have submitted to the relevant department within BHP.

We may disclose your Personal Information to third parties including the authorities, BHP's advisors, suppliers of IT services and third parties engaged by BHP for the purpose of providing services requested by you; to protect any intellectual property rights in any materials displayed on or otherwise available from BHP's website; for the purposes of seeking legal or other professional advice; to respond to a legal request or comply with a legal obligation; and to enforce BHP's website Terms and Conditions of Use.

We may disclose your Personal Information to third parties in the event that we sell, buy or merge any business or assets, including to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets. BHP may also disclose the Personal Information you provide to us via the BHP job vacancy website to BHP HR practitioners, BHP Hiring Managers and to BHP's recruitment advisors for the purpose of considering you for career opportunities with BHP.

Because BHP operates globally, we may share the Personal Information you submit to us with any entity within the BHP group worldwide. These entities are required to maintain the confidentiality of this information and are restricted from using it for any purpose other than the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

**Transfer of your Personal Information to other countries**

Please note that any person to whom BHP may disclose your Personal Information under this Privacy Policy may be situated in a country other than your own and that such country may provide a lower level of data protection requirements than your own country. By agreeing to this Privacy Policy, you consent to the transfer of your Personal Information to a country other than your own.

Whenever we transfer Personal Information across borders, we take steps to put in place adequate safeguards to protect your Personal Information and to make sure it is treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you are located in the European Economic Area or the UK, you can request a copy of the safeguards which we have put in place to protect your Personal Information and privacy rights in these circumstances, using the Contact us form available on our website.

**Access to BHP's e-Business websites**

Access to certain BHP e-Business websites or portals may be provided to BHP's customers, or suppliers in order to conduct e-commerce transactions or for supplier management purposes. Users of BHP's e-Business websites or portals may be required to register with the membership database by providing their e-mail address; their name, company name, office name; their business address, business phone; and a valid BHP internal contact name.

BHP will collect details in the membership database that are relevant to the use of the e-Business website. While BHP will use the registration details for demographic analysis and to personalise your web experience, BHP will not make membership details available to external parties.

**Retention of Personal Information**

BHP’s aim is to keep your Personal Information for no longer than is necessary for regulatory or BHP business reasons. The amount of time that records are kept for varies depending upon the type of Personal Information they contain.

**Your rights in relation to your Personal Information**

If you would like to access or obtain a copy (which may be in machine-readable form) of the Personal Information BHP holds about you, please send a request to ‘General Enquiries’ on the Contact us form available on our website.

BHP endeavours to ensure that the Personal Information it holds about you is complete, accurate and up to date. If you consider that your Personal Information is incomplete, inaccurate or out of date, you have the right to require us to correct it. In order to correct, erase or limit the processing of any of the Personal Information we hold about you, again please send a request via the form on our website.

If you have a live account with our job vacancy website, and we continue to process your Personal Information in connection with that account (see the section headed ‘Job vacancy website’ above for information regarding retention timeframes), you can at all times complete, update or otherwise rectify your Personal Information by logging into your account via the applicant login section of our website.

You may remove any Personal Information you provided to us via BHP's job vacancy website at any time by sending a request to jobs@bhpbilliton.com.

If you do not provide us with the information sought in the required fields we may be limited in our ability to provide you with services.

**Complaints and Concerns**

If you have a concern or complaint about how BHP has used your Personal Information, as a first step, you should raise this in writing with BHP, using the contact details available on our website or via the Contact Us form.

If you are not satisfied with the handling of your concern or complaint by BHP, you can escalate this to your national Data Protection Authority.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy and Contact**

Any changes BHP may make to this Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page.

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be submitted via the Contact Us form available on our website.

**Who we are**

References to BHP in this Privacy Policy mean BHP Group Limited of 171 Collins Street, Melbourne, Victoria 3000, Australia; BHP Group Plc of Nova South, 160 Victoria Street, London, SW1E 5LB, UK; BHP Marketing Asia Pte Ltd of 10 Marina Boulevard, #50-01 Marina Bay Financial Tower, Tower 2, Singapore 018983; or the local BHP entity in the country in which your Personal Information is collected. For a full list of BHP entities, please see here.

**Last updated [22 May 2018]**
